<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-02-26T19:14:15+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Sharc</title><subtitle>Insights into the world of web3 and Decentralization of different platforms.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">What is NFT?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/web3/nft/blockchain/token/digital/2023/01/14/what-is-nft/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is NFT?" /><published>2023-01-14T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2023-01-14T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/web3/nft/blockchain/token/digital/2023/01/14/what-is-nft</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/web3/nft/blockchain/token/digital/2023/01/14/what-is-nft/">&lt;p&gt;An &lt;strong&gt;asset in the physical world that you own is comparable to a NFT&lt;/strong&gt;, like land, car, or house. It can be &lt;strong&gt;unique and scarce, but not necessarily!&lt;/strong&gt; Think about that pencil that you bought yesterday that is also an asset that you own, but that is neither unique not scarce. With an asset in the physical world, you can take it and it sits in your house or similar. And there’s never a question of ownership as it resides with you. Where is Mr. Karkman’s WWII rifle? It sits in Mr. Housmith’s residence. So it should now obviously belong to Mr. Housmith.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With assets in the digital world. Its &lt;strong&gt;difficult to represent ownership&lt;/strong&gt;. You can have a jpeg of your cat and so you might say that you own that image. You send the image to your neighbor who wants to see your cat. And now she has access to the image. And she can claim that she owns the image. She shares it on social. And some cat guy gets obssessed and downloads it from the internet. And shares it in his group and claims its his image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper center&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/watermarkedimage.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;A watermarked image from Shutterstock.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You probably have seen people watermarking their PDFs, images, videos to represent ownership. And obviously there are tools that can be used to remove watermarks from anything. And with recent research in AI, we can remove watermarks or for that matter any kind of marks from images without any hassle and with no marks left on the image that gives off that there was a watermark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have noticed something in the 2010s internet era, &lt;strong&gt;community would call out if they see a copycat trying to claim something that is not theirs&lt;/strong&gt;. Lets say, if there’s some account with a lot of followers, posting a picture(or other asset). And that gets copied by someone and that someone tries to claim its theirs. That doesnt work!! Cause everybody knows its not their work! Everybody saw that asset come out of the popular person’s account. So ideally, this second guy cant claim its his, cause everybody knows the truth. This same thing happens with Linkedin Posts nowadays, where if one post is getting a lot of traction, someone else would just copy paste the entire post without giving credits or anything. The people who know that the other guy is just copying cause they have seen the original post. And there might be some who didnt come across the original ones and thus they keep thinking that this copied one is the original one.!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper center&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/linkedinreposts.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Same content being copy/pasted across the Social Media with successful traction.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you see, it is very &lt;strong&gt;difficult to represent ownership in the digital world&lt;/strong&gt;. Everybody can get their hands on the copy of your image, file, audio, video and other data/assets and can easily claim it is theirs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where blockchain and thus, NFT comes in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article, we are going to see:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#what-is-nft&quot;&gt;What is NFT?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#what-are-nfts-used-for&quot;&gt;What are NFTs used for?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#example-of-nfts&quot;&gt;Example of NFTs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-nft&quot;&gt;What is NFT?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper center&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/assettypes.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Asset Types.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NFT stands of Non-Fungible Token. &lt;strong&gt;They represent ownership of unique digital items&lt;/strong&gt;. We can tokenize any digital asset such as art, pictures, moments, real-estate, game assets, literally anything digital. Ownership of these tokens are secured by the blockchain and nobody can modify the records of these ownership. Just like i was telling that if a post is now seen my millions and now somebody else try to come in and copy paste the same post and try to claim its theirs, nobody would believe this other guy. &lt;strong&gt;Everybody knows what is the truth.&lt;/strong&gt; Similarly, anytime somebody purchases something, or any kind of activity/transaction is recorded in the blockchain. And that means, that everybody now is aware of the truth. And one person claiming something different wont effect the truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Non-fungible&lt;/strong&gt; is an economic term that is used to describe assets which have unique properties, and thus are &lt;strong&gt;not interchangeable for other similar items&lt;/strong&gt;. Like the chair you sit at, or a computer, that is to say any asset with unique properties. &lt;strong&gt;Fugible items&lt;/strong&gt; on the other hand &lt;strong&gt;can be exchanged because their value defines them and not their properties&lt;/strong&gt;. Example would be currencies, like Dollars($)/Indian Rupee, 1Rupee is exchangeable for another 1Rupee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An asset that has physical form is called tangible asset.&lt;/strong&gt; Examples would be any equipment/machinery, Furnitures, Land (not metaverse land), buildings etc. Digital assets, ie assets that dont have a physical form are called &lt;strong&gt;non-tangible assets.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-nfts-used-for&quot;&gt;What are NFTs used for?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NFTs are currently being used to achieve different use-cases! Some are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#digital-content&quot;&gt;Digital Content&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#in-game-assets&quot;&gt;In-Game assets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#domain-names&quot;&gt;Domain Names&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#physical-items&quot;&gt;Physical items&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#nft-backed-loans&quot;&gt;NFT-backed Loans&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#tokengating&quot;&gt;Tokengating&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;digital-content&quot;&gt;Digital Content&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper center&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/hoodenza_overlook.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;A few NFTs from the Hoodenza Collection.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Content creators making content, be it art, written content, audio or video &lt;strong&gt;helps make money for the platform which sells ads to the creators content consumers&lt;/strong&gt;. They get exposure in return. Which is good. Exposure is required but if the unique pieces of content that the creators work on throughout, gets them some money that could help them lead better lives, wouldn’t that be great!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some platforms like &lt;a href=&quot;youtube.com&quot;&gt;Youtube&lt;/a&gt; allow &lt;strong&gt;creators to make money off the ads that are running on their content&lt;/strong&gt;. But not all. NFTs come in exactly at that place, where the creators dont hand over the ownership of their content to the platform they are using to publicise it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from, NFT &lt;strong&gt;enabling creators to sell their content to interested buyers&lt;/strong&gt; who are interested in the art/any form of content that the creator has made. There’s a new concept of Royalties, where the &lt;strong&gt;creator of the content can make some money everytime the content is sold&lt;/strong&gt;. So, without royalties, the creator just makes money when the content is sold first time, as the owner. With royalties, the creator gets royalties everytime the content is transacted irrespective of the new owner, as it is embedded in the chain who the original creator is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper center&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/eulerbeats_royalties.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Eulerbeat Royalty.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Royalties is still a developing concept, at the time of writing this blog. The idea is, if you program royalties in your NFT project then you can just sit back and earn every time a purchase is made!! Right now, it lacks accuracy and creators dont get paid what they deserve, but this is gonna fixed with time. As long as you have &lt;strong&gt;opt in royalties programitacally&lt;/strong&gt; you are good! &lt;a href=&quot;https://eulerbeats.com&quot;&gt;EulerBeats&lt;/a&gt; earn an 8% royalty every time the NFT is sold. Recently Opensea also opted in for creator royalties &lt;a href=&quot;/shorts/2023-02-19-opensea-zero-free/&quot;&gt;read&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-game-assets&quot;&gt;In-game assets&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper center&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/decentraland_ingameassets.png&quot; alt=&quot;MakerDAO&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Decentraland Marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Web3, gaming will take on new heights! Iv explained in-detail how web3 is going to effect gaming here - &lt;a href=&quot;/web3/gaming/games/blockchain/nft/token/2023/01/07/web3-gaming/&quot;&gt;Web3 Gaming&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In brief, you can &lt;strong&gt;own and trade the ingame assets&lt;/strong&gt; that you purchase or receive in the game, &lt;strong&gt;in open marketplaces irrespective of the game where you received it&lt;/strong&gt;. And it can be used in the physical-world to get discounts or can act as passes as these in-game assets are NFTs!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;domain-names&quot;&gt;Domain Names&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper center&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/arcethens.png&quot; alt=&quot;ENS arc.eth&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;arc.eth&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ENS - Ethereum Name Service &lt;strong&gt;provides easier-to-remember names for your eth wallet&lt;/strong&gt; like arc.eth. So instead of remembering someone’s wallet address like 0x829382… they could just simply say “Hey my wallet is arc.eth” and it becomes much more convienient for you to send or receive! Pretty similar to Domain names for IP addresses!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENS utilizes NFTs.&lt;/strong&gt; So you can trade ENS on NFT marketplaces!! CrazY! It provides with all the features that you get with your wallet, as its just a mapping! To mention a few:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Receive cryptocurrency and other NFTs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Point to a decentralized website like &lt;a href=&quot;ethereum.eth&quot;&gt;ethereum.eth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Store other small arbritary information, like links to your different socials.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;physical-items&quot;&gt;Physical Items&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper center&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tangible_physicalnft.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tangible Store&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Tangible Store - Buy real world goods using NFTs.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There has been some projects where there has been &lt;strong&gt;efforts on converting physical items to their digital counterparts!&lt;/strong&gt; Like where if you buy a physical item like a car or shoe or real-estate you would receive an NFT as well that can essentially act as a proof of the ownership of that asset. One such example would be of Nike, they recently launched &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.swoosh.nike/&quot;&gt;swoosh&lt;/a&gt; a web3 platform to sell NFT products!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, you can &lt;strong&gt;get the deeds when you make a purchase like a car or real-estate in the form of NFTs!&lt;/strong&gt; And since your wallet is completely secure it can also act as a key to different physical assets you own!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nft-backed-loans&quot;&gt;NFT-backed loans&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper center&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/makerdao.png&quot; alt=&quot;MakerDAO&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;MakerDAO&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are DeFi applications &lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;Decentralized Finance&lt;/a&gt; that &lt;strong&gt;let you borrow money using collaterals!&lt;/strong&gt; Example of such a platform is &lt;a href=&quot;https://makerdao.com/en/&quot;&gt;MakerDAO&lt;/a&gt;. They allow you to borrow &lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;DAI (Stablecoin)&lt;/a&gt; by keeping other cryptocurrencies as collateral. Like ETH, or BTC. The collateral gurantees that the lender gets paid even if the borrower is not able to return the amount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However it can be the case that you dont have that much amount to keep as collateral, but you own a valuable NFT. So instead of keeping fungible-asset as a token you can ideally be &lt;strong&gt;able to keep a NFT as a collateral&lt;/strong&gt;, which has a required value and that should enable you take the loan as well!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, if you have &lt;strong&gt;NFT of physical assets that you own, you would be able to use that as collateral!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tokengating&quot;&gt;Tokengating&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper center&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/developerdao_gatedcommunity.png&quot; alt=&quot;DeveloperDAO - Gated Community for web3 builders&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;DeveloperDAO - Gated Community for web3 builders.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tokengating is a way to provide access to gated communities/private chat servers/even events that are happening in the physical world with NFTs!&lt;/strong&gt; So you would be able to access a community/event only if you have access to a certain NFT. For a physical event, it can serve the purpose of buying a ticket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same NFT can be used to &lt;strong&gt;provide access to content/community/event across different websites or different events.&lt;/strong&gt; You just have to connect to your wallet and verify that you own the required token and you are good to go! As NFT is all-about-ownership it is one of the most ideal use cases! Communities like Neo Tokyo gate some of their channels and priviledges to only members who have bought certain NFTs! This helps in true community generation and loyalty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The creator also gets to &lt;strong&gt;decide the scarcity of the NFT.&lt;/strong&gt; For example, if the NFT is used to tokengate a movie premiere, then the creator can create 200 exact replicas of the NFT, that would be made available to 200 individuals. Sometimes they can be a bit different like to contain different seat numbers or some special privileges!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;example-of-nfts&quot;&gt;Example of NFTs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper center&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blur.png&quot; alt=&quot;Blur&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Blur NFT Marketplace&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can visit marketplaces like &lt;a href=&quot;opensea.io/&quot;&gt;Opensea&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://blur.io/&quot;&gt;Blur&lt;/a&gt; and checkout the most recent NFT projects from different creators! A few projects and token worth mention would be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper center&quot;&gt;
    

        &lt;video autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot; controls=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot;&gt;
        &lt;source type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; src=&quot;/assets/videos/sneakernft.mp4&quot; alt=&quot;NFT Sneaker&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/video&gt;

    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;NFT Sneaker&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://app.ens.domains/name/arc.eth/&quot;&gt;arc.eth&lt;/a&gt; - ENS example&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An NFT shoe using AI - which enables you to the physical shoe itself &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.metagrail.co/auctions/91cf83fb-3477-4155-aae8-6dcb9b853397&quot;&gt;Metagrail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In game items &lt;a href=&quot;https://market.decentraland.org/&quot;&gt;Decentraland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A NFT ticket that gives you access to physical world events &lt;a href=&quot;https://yh.io/&quot;&gt;yh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Digital Identity &lt;a href=&quot;https://photochromic.io/&quot;&gt;Photochromic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Buy physical goods &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tangible.store/&quot;&gt;Tangible&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cryptopunks - A digital collectible &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptopunks.app/&quot;&gt;Cryptopunks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Degree Certificates as NFT &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.degreecert.com/&quot;&gt;Degreecert&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper center&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/ownership_key.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;NFTs are key to ownership.&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;NFTs are key to ownership.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NFTs allows us to prove ownership of digital assets.&lt;/strong&gt; There has been a lot of activity with NFTs. Billions have been spent on NFT transactions. With the recent media, it might seem like its hype and about monkey pictures and only art, but NFTs are much more than that! Decentralization is much more than that, and NFTs will play an integral part in decentralization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world has already been using NFTs to achieve a lot, as we saw some examples above. Lot of people have made fortunes with NFTs. And many more to come. You dont have to be a creator to understand NFTs, &lt;strong&gt;its for anybody who would require ownership of assets&lt;/strong&gt; in the Web3 era :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
Comparable to NFT in the physical-world in a asset that is unique and scrace. 

You get your hands-on your grandfather's rifle. Who fought WWII with it. And now it stands as a symbol in the western wall of your house. You decide to put it a price on it. And a interested buyer takes it away from you.

Here we can think of the rifle as an NFT. Its an asset. An NFT is an asset. That is unique.



Your grandpa was a world-famous scientist, named, Robert Nakrot. Robert's genetically engineered this mammal, that was a hybrid between a mouse, spider and lizard. Uniquely enough, it had some interesting features. This animal recently passed away. And you have got your hands on it

----
You got your hands on one of the Mark IV deep diving suits. You find yourself on the beach next day. Ready to rock and roll. You put your suit on. Half naked people starring at you! They are like who is this?! You dont care.! You do what you are there for! Put your suit on.! And start running towards the water! People are still starring! Some have pulled their phones out by now. You keep running. And a few minutes later you deep inside the ocean! Ahh! What a feeling! You can see multiple school of fish around you! Some shadows you can see at some distance.

Fast-forward.

You come out of the ocean, with a part of ship that was sunk 1000s of years back! The guys see you coming out of the water and come running towards you. You remove your helmet and smile at them :) You stood their holding your knee, a few deep breaths!

Then you yell-out! &quot;This is a part of ship that sunk 1000s of years back!&quot; You hold it high in your hands. They see it glowing! You yell. Five thousand dollars! And its yours to keep! 

You get a few offers and you make the sale :)

What is the point of this?

That part of the ship is unique and authentic. Nobody on 
--&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="web3" /><category term="nft" /><category term="blockchain" /><category term="token" /><category term="digital" /><summary type="html">An asset in the physical world that you own is comparable to a NFT, like land, car, or house. It can be unique and scarce, but not necessarily! Think about that pencil that you bought yesterday that is also an asset that you own, but that is neither unique not scarce. With an asset in the physical world, you can take it and it sits in your house or similar. And there’s never a question of ownership as it resides with you. Where is Mr. Karkman’s WWII rifle? It sits in Mr. Housmith’s residence. So it should now obviously belong to Mr. Housmith.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/nftgallery_oncyber.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/nftgallery_oncyber.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Web3 Gaming: The future of Gaming!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/web3/gaming/games/blockchain/nft/token/2023/01/07/web3-gaming/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Web3 Gaming: The future of Gaming!" /><published>2023-01-07T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2023-01-07T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/web3/gaming/games/blockchain/nft/token/2023/01/07/web3-gaming</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/web3/gaming/games/blockchain/nft/token/2023/01/07/web3-gaming/">&lt;p&gt;The global gaming market has been valued at $195 billion in 2021 (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.grandviewresearch.com/industry-analysis/video-game-market&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;). In &lt;strong&gt;2021 alone people have spent $54B on in-game items&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/statistics/558952/in-game-consumer-spending-worldwide/&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;). Thats quite a bit of in-game purchases. For those of you who are new to the modern gaming world, in-game purchases are items that can be bought to enhance certain things that are available in the game. Like weapons, outfits, spells, charms, coins and so on. Going forward lets call these assets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--![Fortnite Game Store](/assets/images/ingame_items_fornite.png){:style=&quot;display:block; margin-left:auto; margin-right:auto&quot;}{: width=&quot;380&quot;}--&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper center&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/ingame_items_fornite.png&quot; alt=&quot;title for image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Fornite in-game items&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a traditional gaming setting what would happen is, these purchases that the gamer is making would be very confined to that particular game itself and the gamer wont be able to utilize or use this anywhere outside the game itself. In other words, what that would mean is, &lt;strong&gt;your assets are centralized&lt;/strong&gt; (with the gaming company) and you wont be able to use it anywhere other than inside the game itself! Your asset looses value outside that particular game world! But what if … YES!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are spending money or time and/or doing some crazy things inside the game which makes you eligible for some asset, be it a new weapon or a new outfit or a new charm to hang on your weapon. &lt;strong&gt;Wouldn’t it be great if you could get a discount on your next Starbucks purchase cause you have unlocked that new asset!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper center&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/open_marketplace.png&quot; alt=&quot;title for image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Open Marketplace to trade NFTs&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well that’s just an example of what could happen.! Once your assets become decentralized and has value outside the game world, you can &lt;strong&gt;trade your assets for other things in the open marketplace&lt;/strong&gt; pretty legally and get your hands on some crazy deals!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, what essentially happens is you &lt;strong&gt;get value in the real-world&lt;/strong&gt; from the time and effort you are putting in the game. And this exactly is the reason, Web3 Gaming has seen some major traction and is expected to grow crazily. If you think logically, this is the way forward. Why would anyone prefer otherwise?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We, thus, are going to live in an era, where playing games can give us access to certain private communities, or exclusive shows, or exclusive events or discounts on popular brands and much much more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For this post, we are going to see:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#what-is-web3-gaming&quot;&gt;What is Web3 Gaming?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#main-features-of-web3-gaming&quot;&gt;Main features of Web3 Gaming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#some-web3-games&quot;&gt;Some Web3 games!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-web3-gaming&quot;&gt;What is Web3 Gaming?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper center&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/web3gamingsection.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;title for image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Gaming on Blockchain&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Web3 gaming essentially &lt;strong&gt;decentralizes traditional gaming&lt;/strong&gt;, such that the activities that the gamer perform in the game world, particularly speaking of owning in-game assets and also the decision-making aspects of gaming are delegated away from a central authority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Web3 games are &lt;strong&gt;built on top of a blockchain&lt;/strong&gt;. This allows gamers to express their opinions on when and how the game should evolve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Web3 gaming also enables the foundation of &lt;strong&gt;play-to-earn&lt;/strong&gt; for players and some changes in the &lt;strong&gt;pay-to-play&lt;/strong&gt; model by offering asset trading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;main-features-of-web3-gaming&quot;&gt;Main features of Web3 Gaming&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper center&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/winwin.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Web3 Gaming is a win for both gamers and the Gaming Studios!!&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ownership&lt;/strong&gt; - With games built on top of the blockchain, the games have a value-exchange model where gamers can completely own in-game assets and collectibles as NFTs and trade them as well using cryptocurrencies. In contrast to traditional gaming, where in-game assets has value and use only inside the game, with web3 game assets, gamers get value of them out in the real world!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interoperability&lt;/strong&gt; - The assets that the gamers collect in a particular game can be used in other games on the same or different blockchains (depends). Not just that, these game assets that are now available to the gamers can be traded on the open market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Game Studios&lt;/strong&gt; - Its also a win for the developers and gaming studios, as they can offer in-game assets like characters, land or others - what is relevant for the particular game - in the form of NFTs and thus allowing them to raise money and build a audience before the actual launch of the game!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper center&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/dalle_rareingameitem.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;A scarce to find asset! (AUTO)&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The in-game assets that are offered in a Web3 Game, are basically, NFTs. With NFTs, the quantity of each type of the item is fixed and its origin and history can be tracked, this &lt;strong&gt;gives these assets a authenticity and scarcity!&lt;/strong&gt; That makes it actually valuable and thus some assets can be very hard and rare to get your hands-on!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;some-web3-games&quot;&gt;Some Web3 Games&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cryptokitties&quot;&gt;CryptoKitties&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3PTstAK-cH8/&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;!--&lt;iframe width=&quot;420&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3PTstAK-cH8/&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who&lt;/strong&gt;: Developed by Dapper Labs in 2017. It was one of the first-recorded web3 games in the space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What&lt;/strong&gt;:  In the game, users collect, what are called, CryptoKitties, which are basically NFTs. Once they own a few kitties, they can breed between cryptokitties to generate new cryptokitties, which are also NFTs. And the breeding happens through the combination of the so-called “genes” of these cryptokitties.&lt;br /&gt;
With 1.5 million total users and $40 million worth of transactions on the platform in 2019, the game attracted 14,000 users daily — and made headlines when an in-game pet was sold for $300,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cryptokitties.co/&quot;&gt;CryptoKitties Website&lt;/a&gt;. The open-marketplace to collect and trade cryptokitties is here at &lt;a href=&quot;https://opensea.io/collection/cryptokitties&quot;&gt;OpenSea - CryptoKitties&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;axie-infinity&quot;&gt;Axie Infinity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/X2z_YIeettE/&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;!--&lt;iframe width=&quot;420&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/X2z_YIeettE/&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who&lt;/strong&gt;: Sky Mavix in 2018 March. Another early game in the web3 world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What&lt;/strong&gt;: With a similar model, where users buy their initial characters (in the form of NFTs) and then they perform battles, upgrade, buy lands, and farm resources. There’s also real-time battles where players can earn money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hitting 2.7 million monthly active users in January 2022 (source - CoinDCX).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://axieinfinity.com/&quot;&gt;Axie Infinity&lt;/a&gt;. They have their own marketplace!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-sandbox&quot;&gt;The Sandbox&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0Jquhzr4d4k/&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;!--&lt;iframe width=&quot;420&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0Jquhzr4d4k/&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who&lt;/strong&gt; - PIXOWL INC in 2012&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What&lt;/strong&gt;: One of the first games to &lt;strong&gt;offer land on the metaverse&lt;/strong&gt;, in the form of NFTs. The goal of the game is to create experiences like Minecraft on the blockchain and thus essentially disrupt games like Minecraft. Its a platform where users can build, own and monetize their gaming experiences. You can create your own avatar for free to get started!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where&lt;/strong&gt;:  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sandbox.game/en/&quot;&gt;The Sandbox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Web3 gaming is inevitable. Gaming is a growing sector and &lt;strong&gt;giving gamers ownership&lt;/strong&gt; and thus ideally in one word, freedom, is definitely something that the gamers want and thus will happen.!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper center&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/dalle_aguywithjoy.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;A gamer having the fun! (AUTO)&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, with web3 gaming, theres a &lt;strong&gt;community of the gamers who are continously active and giving feedback throughout the process of the development&lt;/strong&gt; of the game, and thus the desire is pretty prevalent, which allows the gaming studios / developers build it exactly for the demand. Also, the studios can raise money for in-game items before even the game is launched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in short, yeah, it is &lt;strong&gt;in-evitable!&lt;/strong&gt; :)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="web3" /><category term="gaming" /><category term="games" /><category term="blockchain" /><category term="nft" /><category term="token" /><summary type="html">The global gaming market has been valued at $195 billion in 2021 (source). In 2021 alone people have spent $54B on in-game items (source). Thats quite a bit of in-game purchases. For those of you who are new to the modern gaming world, in-game purchases are items that can be bought to enhance certain things that are available in the game. Like weapons, outfits, spells, charms, coins and so on. Going forward lets call these assets.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/web3gaming_header.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/web3gaming_header.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>